module.exports = {
    decks: {
        0: {
            id: 0,
            deck: 'Mendelâ€™s Genetics',
            cards: [
                {
                    question: 'Offspring that are the result of mating between two genetically different kinds of parents--the opposite of purebred.',
                    answer: 'Hybrid'
                },
                {
                    question: 'The study of gene structure and action and the patterns of inheritance of traits from parent to offspring.  This is the branch of science that deals with the inheritance of biological characteristics.',
                    answer: 'Genetics'
                },
                {
                    question: 'A 19th century central European monk scientist who published his ideas about genetics in 1866 but largely went unrecognized until 1900, which was long after his death.  He acquired his understanding of genetics mostly through pea plant breeding experiments.',
                    answer: 'Gregor Mendel'
                },
                {
                    question: 'A theory that inherited traits blend from generation to generation.  Most of the leading scientists in the 19th century accepted it.  However, Gregor Mendel proved that it was not correct.',
                    answer: 'Blending theory'
                },
                {
                    question: 'Offspring that are the result of mating between genetically similar kinds of parents--the opposite of hybrid.',
                    answer: 'Purebred'
                }
            ]
        },
        1: {
            id: 1,
            deck: 'Probability of Inheritance',
            cards: [
                {
                    question: 'A simple graphical method of showing all of the potential combinations of offspring genotypes that can occur and their probability given the parent genotypes.  This system involves the use of a tic-tac-toe square.  It was named after pioneer British geneticist.',
                    answer: 'Punnett square'
                },
                {
                    question: 'The term for a genotype in which there are two dominant alleles.',
                    answer: 'Homozygous Dominant'
                },
                {
                    question: 'The term for a genotype in which there is a dominant allele and a recessive one.',
                    answer: 'Heterozygous'
                },
                {
                    question: 'The term for a genotype in which there are two recessive alleles.',
                    answer: 'Homozygous Recessive'
                },
                {
                    question: 'The genotype of an individual who is a carrier for a recessive allele that is not expressed in his/her phenotype.',
                    answer: 'heterozygous'
                }
            ]
        },
        2: {
            id: 2,
            deck: 'Exceptions to Simple Inheritance',
            cards: [
                {
                    question: 'The general term for inheritance patterns which can be explained by simple rules of dominance and receptiveness of genes.',
                    answer: 'Mendelian Genetics'
                },
                {
                    question: 'The inheritance pattern in which a trait is expressed in the phenotype of heterozygous individuals as an apparent blend or an intermediate expression.  For instance, in primroses white flowers are homozygous recessive, red ones are homozygous dominant, and pink ones are heterozygous. ',
                    answer: 'incomplete dominance'
                },
                {
                    question: 'The inheritance pattern in which two different alleles for a trait are expressed unblended in the phenotype of heterozygous individuals.  Type AB human blood is an example.',
                    answer: 'codominance'
                },
                {
                    question: 'An inheritance pattern in which a gene has more than two alleles.  The human ABO blood type system is an example.  It is controlled by at least 3 alleles.',
                    answer: 'multiple-allele series'
                },
                {
                    question: 'Genes that can alter how certain other genes are expressed in the phenotype.  Genes causing some kinds of cataracts can be affected by such accompanying genes.',
                    answer: 'modifying genes'
                },

            ]
        },
        3: {
            id: 3,
            deck: 'Mendelian Genetics',
            cards: [
                {
                    question: 'Offspring that are the result of mating between two genetically different kinds of parents--the opposite of purebred.',
                    answer: 'Hybrid'
                },
                {
                    question: 'The study of gene structure and action and the patterns of inheritance of traits from parent to offspring.  This is the branch of science that deals with the inheritance of biological characteristics.',
                    answer: 'Genetics'
                },
                {
                    question: 'A 19th century central European monk scientist who published his ideas about genetics in 1866 but largely went unrecognized until 1900, which was long after his death.  He acquired his understanding of genetics mostly through pea plant breeding experiments.',
                    answer: 'Gregor Mendel'
                },
                {
                    question: 'A theory that inherited traits blend from generation to generation.  Most of the leading scientists in the 19th century accepted it.  However, Gregor Mendel proved that it was not correct.',
                    answer: 'Blending theory'
                },
                {
                    question: 'Offspring that are the result of mating between genetically similar kinds of parents--the opposite of hybrid.',
                    answer: 'Purebred'
                }
            ]
        },
    }
};

